Hey Chris.
嗨 Chris
&gt;&gt; Hi Trinh.
嗨 Trinh
&gt;&gt; Over the past year that we've been working together on the careers team at
在过去一年里 我们一直在优达学城的职业团队
Udacity, you've developed so much, so many of our web apps, so
共事 你帮我们开发了很多 Web 应用
many of our data backend, and I was really surprised when I learned that
很多数据后端 但是我了解到你实际做软件工程师
you've actually only been a software engineer for a year, and so
只有一年 我真的很惊讶
I'm just really curious to see how you got here?
很想知道你是怎么做到的？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's right.
是的 你说的是对的
I've been a software engineer at Udacity for a year,
我在优达学城担任软件工程师只有一年
and my career I guess started a little bit more than ten years ago.
但是我的职业生涯大约从十年前就开始了
I was originally a admission counselor, and I got into tutoring and teaching.
刚开始我是一名招生顾问 之后做过辅导和教学
I even did a stint as an administrator working at a psychiatrist office
我还曾在一名心理医生的办公室做过管理员
learning about medicine and health insurance.
在那里学习了医疗保险方面的知识
&gt;&gt; Well that's like a really diverse background.
听起来你的经验还挺丰富多彩的
How did you end up from a psychiatrist office to being a software engineer?
那么 你是怎么从心理医生办公室管理员变成一名软件工程师的呢？
&gt;&gt; So, it was definitely a long, winding road.
事实上 这个过程有点长 有点曲折
I think for
我觉得
me, I first got curious about software engineering through teaching.
刚一开始我是在教学的过程中对软件工程产生了兴趣
I made some courses at Udacity, in math and data analysis and product design.
我在优达学城制作了一些数学、数据分析和产品设计方面的课程
And along the way, I picked up coding skills, so
在这个过程中 我偶然学到了一些编码技能
I learned a little bit about Python, I learned JavaScript.
接触了 Python 并学习了 JavaScript
I learned how to think computationally,
我学会了从计算机方面去思考问题
how to think kind of more like a computer scientist.
学习计算机科学家的思维方式
And I've just been learning ever since.
就这样不断地学习
And for me, I think, the biggest thing was trying to
对于我来说 我认为最大的挑战是尝试
acquire all those skills and then convince people that I had enough skills
获得所有这些技能 并让别人信服我具有足够的技能
to build something and to contribute to a larger organization.
来构建实际的东西 并在一个大型的团体里做出贡献
&gt;&gt; That's great that you brought that up.
你提到的这一点非常好
I speak with a lot of people about their career development and so
我和很多人聊过职业发展
many of them took the initiative,
大多数人都会主动去学习
like you, to learn on their own time, some while they're working full time.
就像你一样 在做全职工作的同时利用自己的时间学习一些新知识
But they still kind of face a barrier in that the it's hard for
但是他们会也会遇到一个障碍 那就是
them to convince people that, yes I am qualified and
很难让他人相信你有这方面合格的能力 让他人信服即使
yes even though I don't have background in this job, I can still do it.
我没有这方面的工作背景 但是我可以做同样的事情
How did you approach that problem?
那么 你是怎么解决这个问题的呢？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I mean it's certainly a hard one and I think it's easy to feel like
是的 这确实是一个棘手的难题 在这种情况下你很容易会觉得
you're an imposter, or you don't have enough skills.
自己是冒牌的 自己并不够格
And I think the biggest thing you can do is one, practice, but also two,
这个时候 我觉得你要做的第一件事是练习 第二件是
tell yourself that you are a software engineer.
告诉自己你就是一名软件工程师
Talk about your projects.
和他人谈论你的项目
Talk about them technically with other people.
从技术的角度去谈论这些项目
That will build your confidence in your own abilities and
这会让你对自己的能力建立自信
your ability to communicate that you can do this work.
并传达一个信息 那就是你可以做到
So I think for me, I know one of the things that I had to do was just kind of
所以对我来说 需要做的最重要的一点是
turn off that voice in my head that says you're not good enough.
关掉脑海中说“我不行”
Or you don't know enough things.
或“我还欠缺很多知识”的那个声音
Just turn off that imposter syndrome entirely and talk about what I can do,
完全摆脱冒充者的心理 而是谈论我可以做什么
what I have done.
以及我的成果
And that's what can really help you get an interview and
这些真的会帮助你获得面试机会
succeed in those interviews.
并且成功通过面试
&gt;&gt; A lot of people when they're transitioning to a new career for
很多人在第一次转型到新的职业时
the first time, it's really hard for them to introduce themselves and
他们不知道如何去介绍自己
package everything that you just said about yourself into kind of a short
将你刚才所说的这些方面总结起来
introduction to other people.
简短地向他人概括自己
So do you have any strategies on how people can approach talking
那么你有什么好的策略 来与他人
to other people about their career change?
谈论职业变化吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah I think one of the best things that you can do is to use
是的 我觉得最好的一个办法是
an elevator pitch.
电梯演讲